{
    "questions": [
        {
            "options": [
                "B. 1971",
                "C. 1947",
                "D. 1960"
            ],
            "question": "In which year, Assamese was adopted as the official language of Assam?A. 1985",
            "answer": "D. 1960"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. 1911",
                "C. 1924",
                "D. 1941"
            ],
            "question": "In which year Tocklai Tea Research Institute was established?A. 1903",
            "answer": "B. 1911"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Subankhata",
                "C. Silbheta",
                "D. Hahim"
            ],
            "question": "In which of the following area in Assam iron ore deposits are found?A. Chanderdinga Hills"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. 1000 km",
                "C. 1500 km",
                "D. 2100 km"
            ],
            "question": "In India, the Brahmaputra river is almost ___ km long.A. 900 km"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Mizoram",
                "C. Sikkim",
                "D. NagalandAnswer: B",
                "B. 1973",
                "C. 1984",
                "D. 1993"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following state is not situated to the east of Assam?A. Manipur",
            "answer": "B. Mizoram"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Singhasan",
                "C. Rengma",
                "D. DambuksuAnswer: B",
                "B. Doda Betta",
                "C. Guru Peak",
                "D. Himagiri"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following is the highest peak in Karbi Plateau?A. Barail"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Dihing Patkai National Park",
                "C. Nameri National Park",
                "D. Pobitord WLS"
            ],
            "question": "Tropical wet evergreen forests are predominantly found in which of the following protected areas?A. Kaziranga National Park",
            "answer": "B. Dihing Patkai National Park"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Mizoram",
                "C. Tripura",
                "D. Manipur"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following North Eastern state shares the shortest boundary with Assam?A. Nagaland",
            "answer": "C. Tripura"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Indomalaya ecozone",
                "C. IndoBangla ecozone",
                "D. Brahmaputra ecozone"
            ],
            "question": "The Kaziranga National park is located in which of the following ecozones?A. Indoburmese ecozone",
            "answer": "B. Indomalaya ecozone"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. 1899",
                "C. 1900",
                "D. 1918"
            ],
            "question": "When the Tea company of Assam was established?A. 1839"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Pre-monsoon season",
                "C. Retreating monsoon season",
                "D. Winter season"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following is associated with Bordoichila in Assam?A. Monsoon seasonb",
            "answer": "B. Pre-monsoon season"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Third",
                "C. Fourth",
                "D. First"
            ],
            "question": "Area wise the rank of Assam among north eastern states isA. Second"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Karbi Anglong",
                "C. Cachar",
                "D. Dima HasaoAnswer: D",
                "B. 1971",
                "C. 1972",
                "D. 1973"
            ],
            "question": "Jatinga, famous for mass suicide of migratory birds is located in which the following district?A. Golaghat"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Udalguri",
                "C. Chirang",
                "D. Kokrajhar"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following districts of Assam does not come under the jurisdiction of BTC?A. Bongaigaon"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Darrang",
                "C. Barpeta",
                "D. Sonitpur"
            ],
            "question": "Amchang Wildlife Sanctuary is located in which of the following districts in Assam ?A. Kamrup (M)"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Dikhou",
                "C. Disanq",
                "D. Dikrong"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following is a North Bank tributary of Assam?A. Dibru",
            "answer": "D. Dikrong"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. 67456 km²",
                "C. 56789 km²",
                "D. 78438 km²"
            ],
            "question": "What is the total land area of assam ?A. 78534 km²",
            "answer": "D. 78438 km²"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Dhubri",
                "C. Hailakandi",
                "D. Cachar"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following districts of Assam does not have any international boundary with Bangladesh?A. Karimgarj",
            "answer": "C. Hailakandi"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Pagladiya",
                "C. Manas",
                "D. Dibru"
            ],
            "question": "Which of following is the westernmost tributary of Brahmaputra ?A. Sankosh"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Kaziranga National Park and Manas National Park",
                "C. Borail Wildlife Sanctuary and Nokrek National Park",
                "D. None of the sites in Assam are UNESCO World Heritage SiteAnswer: B",
                "B. 24.5%",
                "C. 27.5%",
                "D. 17.7%"
            ],
            "question": "Which the protective sites of Assam are recognised as UNESCO World Heritage Sites?A. Kaziranga National Park and Orang National Park",
            "answer": "D. None of the sites in Assam are UNESCO World Heritage SiteAnswer: B"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 21",
                "B. 16",
                "C. 41",
                "D. 31"
            ],
            "question": "Sex ratio wise the rank of Assam among the states of India is",
            "answer": "B. 16"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Tobbaco",
                "C. Soyabean",
                "D. Mesto"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following cash crops is not produced in Assam?A. Rapeseed",
            "answer": "C. Soyabean"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. High Moisture content",
                "C. Low Volatile Matter",
                "D. High Ash content"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following is true regarding the coals found in Assam?A. High Sulphur content"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Sivasagar",
                "C. Darang",
                "D. DibrugarhAnswer: D",
                "B. Dihang",
                "C. Lohit",
                "D. BrahmaputraAnswer: C",
                "B. 92.5 m",
                "C. 56.6 m",
                "D. 79.5 m"
            ],
            "question": "Which district of Assam has the highest number of Tea gardens ?A. Sonitpur",
            "answer": "D. DibrugarhAnswer: D"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Barauni refinery",
                "C. Noonmati refinery",
                "D. Numaligarh refineryAnswer: A",
                "B. Bogibeel rainforest",
                "C. Dehing Patkai rainforest",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "______ is the oldest refinery of IndiA. A. Digboi refinery",
            "answer": "C. Noonmati refinery"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Dima Hasao",
                "B. Dhubri",
                "C. Karbi Anglong",
                "D. Hailakandi"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following districts of Assam has the lowest literacy rate?",
            "answer": "B. Dhubri"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Winter Rice",
                "C. Summer Rice",
                "D. Autumn Rice"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following is type of rice has the highest production and also highest area under cultivation in Assam?A. Aromatic Rice"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Muga Silk",
                "C. Gamocha",
                "D. Both [B] and [C]"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following product/products in Assam has/have Geographical Indication (GI) tag?A. Assam Orthodox Tea",
            "answer": "D. Both [B] and [C]"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. 1824",
                "C. 1825",
                "D. 1826"
            ],
            "question": "In which of the following year Tea was discovered in Assam?A. 1823"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Kamrup",
                "C. Nagaon",
                "D. Barpeta"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following districts in Assam has the highest population?A. Dhubri",
            "answer": "C. Nagaon"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Tezpur",
                "C. Silchar",
                "D. MangaldoiAnswer: A",
                "B. Garampani Wildlife Sanctuary",
                "C. Dibru Saikhowa National Park",
                "D. None of the above"
            ],
            "question": "Which Lok Sabha constituency of Assam is reserved for SC?A. Karimganj",
            "answer": "C. Silchar"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. 72%",
                "C. 82%",
                "D. 85%"
            ],
            "question": "As per the data of 2011 population census, the literacy rate in Assam is approximatelyA. 68%",
            "answer": "B. 72%"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. 1948",
                "C. 1958",
                "D. 1967"
            ],
            "question": "When did Transport Department of Assam was established?A. 1935",
            "answer": "B. 1948"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Hojai and Barpeta",
                "C. Nagaon and Morigaon",
                "D. Kukrajhar and Golaghat"
            ],
            "question": "The major reserves of limestone are in _____ andA. Dima Hasao and Karbi Anglong"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. 24",
                "C. 26",
                "D. 10"
            ],
            "question": "Population wise rank of Assam among the states of India isA. 15"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Second",
                "C. Third",
                "D. Fourth"
            ],
            "question": "The rank of Assam in terms of crude oil production is _____.A. First",
            "answer": "B. Second"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Bhutan and Bangladesh",
                "C. China, Myanmar, Bhutan and Bangladesh",
                "D. Myanmar and Bangladesh"
            ],
            "question": "Assam share international border with which of the following countriesA. Myanmar, Bhutan and Bangladesh",
            "answer": "B. Bhutan and Bangladesh"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Sunderlal Bahuguna",
                "C. Jadav Payeng",
                "D. Kallen PakkudanAnswer: C",
                "B. Pobitora Wildlife Sanctuary",
                "C. Garampani Wildlife Sanctuary",
                "D. Chakrasila Wildlife Sanctuary"
            ],
            "question": "Who is famously known as the “Forest Man of India”?A. Mike Pandey",
            "answer": "D. Kallen PakkudanAnswer: C"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. 10 February, 2003",
                "D. 20 June, 2005"
            ],
            "question": "When did B. T.A. D was established ?A. 30 November, 2004",
            "answer": "B. 10 February, 2003"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. 27",
                "C. 32",
                "D. 34"
            ],
            "question": "The total number of administrative districts in Assam is _________.A. 23",
            "answer": "D. 34"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. 33",
                "C. 80",
                "D. 126"
            ],
            "question": "The total number of seats in the legislative council of Assam is \t.A. 13",
            "answer": "D. 126"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Rubber",
                "C. Maize",
                "D. Paddy"
            ],
            "question": "Assam is not a traditional growing area of which of the following crop?A. Tobacco"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Mikir Hills",
                "C. Singrimari Hills",
                "D. Makum"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following is the largest Coalfield in Assam?A. Dilli Jaypore",
            "answer": "D. Makum"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 14",
                "B. 24",
                "C. 34",
                "D. 44"
            ],
            "question": "The percentage of population living in urban areas in Assam according to 2011 census is",
            "answer": "A. 14"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. 20.6 %",
                "C. 22.4 %",
                "D. 34.21 %"
            ],
            "question": "How much land of assam has been occupied by forests?A. 17.2 %",
            "answer": "D. 34.21 %"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Kokrajhar",
                "C. Baks",
                "D. CacharAnswer: A",
                "B. Kumri Beel Lake",
                "C. Cahndubi Lake",
                "D. Deepor Beel"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following districts of Assam does not have any international boundary?A. Dhemaji"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. 2007",
                "C. 2008",
                "D. 2009"
            ],
            "question": "In which year Kaziranga National Park became a Tiger reserve?A. 2006"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Borgang",
                "C. Jhanji",
                "D. BhugdoiAnswer: C",
                "B. 1867",
                "C. 1889",
                "D. 1901"
            ],
            "question": "Which is the northward flow sub-river of Brahmaputra?A. Ronga Noi"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Guwahati",
                "B. Bongaigaon",
                "C. Numalighar",
                "D. Makum"
            ],
            "question": "Asia’s first successful mechanically drilled oil well was drilled in ________ of Assam way back in 1867.",
            "answer": "D. Makum"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "B. Majuli Island",
                "C. Brahmaputrd Floodplains of Eastern Assam",
                "D. BTAD gred near Bhutan Himalayan foothills"
            ],
            "question": "Red Laterite Soils are found in which of the following areas in AssamA. Karbi Hills and Dima Hasao"
        }
    ]
}